Aniket Balu Suryawanshi

S3D & E3D Administrator

Mobile: +91 8956664150

Email: Asuryawanshi206@gmail.com

Summary

S3D & E3D Administrator with 4+ years of experience in the EPC industry which includes Project Engineering, Piping Design and Administration of Smart Plant tool. Useful Understanding of software's like S3D, Aveva E3D, SmartPlant Review, SQL and AutoCAD. Comprehensive methods to integrate model using 3D software's also engaging in Data-centric Project work. Graduated with a degree in mechanical engineering. Solid background in Software Aveva E3D design, Isograft, Draw modules, E3D-Admininstration & Paragon module for piping catalogues and pipe specification, Auto desk Navisworks, Bentley micro station Certificate in MS Office, AutoCAD, Programming Languages known as python, Aveva PML.

Experience Highlights

2023 - 2023	Systems Engineer, E3D Administrator, Wood Plc, Kolkata
2023 - 2023	EDS Coordinator I, S3D & E3D Administrator, Worley India Pvt Ltd, Vadodara
2022-2023	E3D Administrator, L&T S&L , Vadodara
2021-2022	Piping Engineer, Parason machinery India Pvt. Ltd., Aurangabad, Maharashtra
2019-2021	Associate Piping Designer, Tata consulting engineers Limited, Navi Mumbai

Software Skills

- Smart Plant 3D Admin
- Aveva E3D Admin, Design, Draw
- PDS Admin
- Smart Plant Review
- AutoCAD
- Navisworks
- PML

Education

2019-2022	Bachelor's degree in mechanical engineering, Dr. BAMU university, India,	
	ICEEM college of engineering, Aurangabad (Maharashtra)	8.7 CGPA
2016-2019	Diploma in Mechanical Engineering, MSBTE, Mumbai, India	
	Government polytechnic, Jalna (Maharashtra)	73.65 %

06/2023 - 07/2023

Systems Engineer, E3D Administrator, Woodplc, Kolkata

1. Wood Global catalogue (WGC) (E3D)

- Catalogue Creation as per Wood master PMS
- Naming convention as per Wood global naming convention std to catalogues

01/2023 - 06/2023

E3D & S3D Administrator, Worley, Vadodara

1. Project Name - MGS III Aramco (S3D)

- Installation and configuration of S3D
- Project Setup as per Company requirement
- Provide Project Database and Model Access to user
- Project Database and Model Upgradation from S3D 2016 to S3D 2019 Version
- Model Data Reuse & Model Data Transformation for replicating model
- Preparing Report formats and modification as per requirement
- Generation of model review files for Smart Plant Review and Navisworks
- Batch schedule for daily updating for Review files, Reports, Backups etc.
- Project maintenance & View generation
- Border Setup for Drawings and Isometrics
- Attribute Customization for Equipment, Structure and Piping
- Surface Style and View Style Customization
- Prepare and maintain 3D procedures
- Modification of Label rules & Dimension rules in Drawing View style
- User Troubleshooting

2. Project Name – British Petroleum - BP khazzan (S3D & PDS) S3D

- Project Setup from Client provided S3D backup
- Installation and configuration of S3D
- Project Database and Model Upgradation from S3D 2016 to S3D 2019 Version
- Provide Project Database and Model access to user
- Generation of Model review files for SmartPlant Review and Navisworks
- Preparing Report formats and modification as per requirement
- Batch schedule of project Backup and model review
- Project maintenance & view generation
- Model Data Reuse & Model Data Transformation for replicating model
- User Troubleshooting
- LFM dataset linking in Aveva Point cloud manager with S3D point cloud model
- Prepare and maintain 3D procedures

PDS

- PDS client configuration
- · Creation of PDS Design areas, models, and Sub project for FWP
- Archive and retrieval of PDS models
- Taking backup of PDS models (RIS Dump), Load\unload RIS dump
- Report Manager extraction of reports & format modification.
- Extracting RDB, data verification & design checks reports
- Creation of clash areas and performs clash check
- To extract different reports as CPS, Instruments, Insulation, MTO reports etc.
- SPR and Navis session creation

3. Project Name – Near zero liquid discharge (NZLD) (E3D)

- Creation, Modify Piping catalogue, piping specifications,
- E3D Spec creation and Catalogue updating. Specification, Catalogue, User Defined Attributes, Properties, Material Text, etc.)
- Extracting Microsoft excels files compatible MTO from E3D
- Installation, setup of AvevaE3D, setup of teams, users, databases, and all admin activities including Complete project set up creation of Site with required hierarchy.
- E3D Databases Administration involving Teams, Users, DB's MDB creation and modification, Access control rights management ACR.
- Integration between E3D & PDMS.
- Catalogue Customization for instrument Hookups.
- Project Database backup on daily basis
- Navisworks NWD Review File generation on daily basis from E3D and maintain attribute file.
- Speciality item catalogues modelling like MOV valves, strainers, flame arrestors. Etc.
- Creation & Maintaining pipe specifications according to PMS received.
- Able to modify Isometric option file according to client requirement.
- Draw module administration.
- Creating backing sheets, SLAB, modification of GLAB, Customization of sheet as per client requirement.
- Setting Up MDS and MDU supports in E3D.

06/2022 - 01/2023 Jr. piping engineer, Larsen & toubro (L&T) -Sargent & Lundy LLC., Vadodara Project Name – IEC Rutenberg Units 1,2,3 & 4.

Israel Electric corporation power plant project setup, admin activities in Aveva E3D, catalogue creation, project initiation. Rutenberg plant ownership of Israel electric corporation IEC is a Conversion from coal based to Natural gas situated in Israel.

11/2021 - 06/2022 Piping Engineer, Parason machinery India Pvt. Ltd., Aurangabad, Maharashtra

Project 1: Suvarna Durga Hyderabad Working on 3D model generation by using E3D software for the client Suvarna Durga paper mills situated in Hyderabad.

Project 2: Phoenix project using E3D and extraction of ISO, GA, PLOT PLAN is done. developed 3D model for this project.

Project 1: HPCL Mumbai

3D model development from laser scanning for HPCL Mumbai refinery(O&G) Client HPCL

Project 2: NAYARA energy limited

Worked on 3D model for Nayara energy limited plant situated in Mumbai, Maharashtra (O&G) Client - Nayara energy limited.

Project 3: Oerlikon textiles pvt. Ltd.

Working on 3D Model creation for Oerlikon project which is basically for ammonia generation purpose. Situated in Bangladesh.

Project 4: Smartchem technologies limited (STL)

Working on 3D Model creation for Smartchem project which is basically for ammonia generation purpose. Client Deepak fertilizers (STL)

Skills

SP3D Admin:

- Installing and Configuring SQL/Oracle for S3D
- Database Maintenance & Database Integrity.
- Import/Exporting ZVF and XML files for R3D referencing.
- Convert DGN to ZVF and create folder hierarchy for R3D Models
- Installing and Configuring Intergraph Batch Services
- Creation of Permission Groups and assigning of Permissions
- Project and Database Up-gradation
- Setup the environment for Restoring the client Backup.
- Backup & Recovery
- Backup Management.
- SQL Database backup.
- Using of MDR (Model Data Reuse) and Troubleshooting.
- · Batch services for Backups.
- Design Review Creation
- Generating review files from Direct SPR method
- Generating SPR from 3DModel Data method
- · Converting .Vue files into Navisworks
- · Importing MicroStation DGN Border file
- Training captured on Smart Sketch and Drawing Editor
- Training captured on the creation, Updating and troubleshooting of Composed Drawings, Volume drawings, Snapshot Drawing
- View style customization specific to discipline deliverables
- Creation of labels for label rules and dimension rules in Drawing View Style

E3D Design, Draw, Isodraft

- Able to create, Modify Piping design.
- Equipment Modelling as per GA received from vendor or client in E3D. nozzle orientation
- Piping modelling using P&ID'S input convenient way.
- Extraction of piping Isometrics using E3D Isodraft and getting comments resolved as per comments received on piping isometrics and issue revisions.
- Extraction of piping arrangement Drawings using E3D Draw module and issue the revisions.
 Read & understand Plant layout and model the piping accordingly
 Piping support modelling as per support mark up.
- Support MTO, Pipe BOQ generation from E3D Report

Languages

Multilingual: Fluent in English, Hindi, and Marathi.

